准备好了吗  孩子们
Are you ready, kids?
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
我听不见
I can't hear you
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
是谁住在深海的大菠萝里
Who lives in a pineapple under the sea?
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
方方黄黄伸缩自如
Absorbent and yellow and porous is he
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
如果四处探险是你的愿望
If nautical nonsense be something you wish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
那就敲敲甲板让大鱼开路
Then drop on the deck and flop like a fish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
准备
Ready
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
抢救时空大作战                                上集
编剧
分镜总监
翻译: 1440kHz
指导总监
动画总监
统筹
监制
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
在缓缓流淌的河上喝冷饮最爽了
Nothing beats a cool drink on a lazy river
对吧  派大星
eh, Patrick?
还真是  兄弟
You said it, pal!
瀑布
Waterfall!
手套乐园感谢你们游玩挫伤瀑布
Glove World thanks you for riding Contusion Falls.
欢迎康复后再来
Come again, after you've healed.
我们会来的
We will!
可能没等康复就来了
Could be sooner!
派大星
Patrick!
今天最棒的时间要来了
It's the best time of the day!
烧烤时间吗
Barbecue time?
不对
Nope!
我说的是做剪贴簿的时间
I'm talking about scrapbooking!
我们要把今天的记忆保存一辈子
We're gonna save the memory of today forever!
一辈子
Forever!
好耶
Oh boy!
怎么
What the...?
来看看
Let's see.
往日时光  美好往日时光
The old days, good old days...
找到了
Here it is!
你就该放《经典》这本里
You belong with the classics!
好了
There.
这下我能永远记住今天的点点滴滴了
Now I'll always remember today exactly as it happened!
回首往事
Memory lane!
我一直都很想要想起来
I've always wanted to remember
记得起事情
to remember things!
记得这个吗
Remember this?
我会飞的那会儿
When I could fly?
不记得
Nope.
好吧
Oh, well...
那这个呢
How about this one?
我们在泡泡碗演出的那会儿
When we performed at the Bubble Bowl?
不记得
No.
那你一定记得
Well, you'll definitely remember...
我撕破我自己裤子的那会儿
when I ripped my pants!
你确定自己真记得吗
You sure you remember it?
那张好像是我爸撕破你裤子才对
'Cause that looks like my dad ripped your pants!
真奇怪
That's odd.
我记得自己有撕破过我裤子啊
I definitely remember ripping my pants.
但不记得自己变过你爸
But I don't remember being your dad.
还有你妈
Or your mom.
还有你爷爷
Or your grandpa!
对了
Oh, yeah!
这些人我一个都不记得
I don't remember any of those people!
派大星
Patrick!
知道那是什么意思吗
Do you know what that means?
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob!
我不知道
I do not.
意思就是出现了大坏事
It means something terrible is going on!
必须马上就去你爸妈家
We have to get to your parents' house right away!
《珍藏回忆》
高菲高伯
老兄
Garçon!
再来一桌双球圣代
Another round of double-scoop sundaes
麻烦了
s'il vous plaît!
你们两个就不能滚别的地方去吗
Don't you two have somewhere else to be?
我的天啊
Oh my gosh!
他说得对
He's right!
那圣代就打包吧
Better make those sundaes to go!
在吗
Hello?
海星爸妈
Mr. And Mrs. Star?
是厨房
The kitchen!
老妈肯定在下厨
Mom must be cooking!
你在这啊
There you are!
天啊
Oh boy!
老妈一定在做她的招牌垃圾砂锅
Mom must be making her famous trasherole!
烤面包机发疯了  好像还饿着肚子
The toaster's gone feral and it seems hungry.
快
Hurry!
给它喂你钱包吃
Let's feed it your wallet!
你反应可真快  派大星
Quick thinking, Patrick.
我突然反应出来  家人就在楼上
Now I'm quick thinking that my family's upstairs.
走吧
Let's go!
我爸跟派大爷
Between my dad and GrandPat
总有一个会在上厕所
someone's always in the bathroom!
在吗
Hello?!
有没有人
Anyone in here?
一定是老爸
Must be Dad.
派大爷从来不冲水
GrandPat never flushes.
阿尿也发疯了
Tinkle's gone feral too.
这下有点乱套了
This is a bit of a mess.
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob!
我想到了
That's it!
乱套
A mess!
来吧
Come on!
我的旧房间
My old room.
还是原状
Just like I left it!
里面可能会有线索
Maybe there's clues in here
能帮我们找到大家的下落
about where everyone went!
可以来扮演侦探了
We get to play detective!
别忘了  再小的线索也不能放过
Remember, no clue is too small!
这颗花生是线索吗
Is this peanut a clue?
干得漂亮  海绵侦探
Good work, Detective SquarePants.
让我看看
Let me see.
不是线索
Not a clue
再找到线索就跟我说一声
but let me know if you find more.
这片隐形眼镜是线索吗
Is this contact lens a clue?
不对  那是我的
No, that's mine.
不小心掉了
Just fell out.
还给你
Here you go!
多谢了
Why, thank you!
给我退后  你这怪物
Stand back, you monster!
海绵宝宝会空手道
SpongeBob knows karate
而且我敢让他来对你耍几招
and I'm not afraid to make him use it!
我不想跟你们打架
I don't want to fight you.
我需要你们帮忙
I need your help!
鱿鱼妹
Squidina!
谢天谢地
Thank goodness!
我们到处都在找你跟你家人
We've been looking everywhere for you and your family!
他们不在这里
Well, you won't find them here.
一切都要从派大星的时旅柜说起
It all started with Patrick's Time Closet
事情就发生在几周前
a few weeks ago...
派大星应该不介意我
Patrick won't mind if I store
往里面存点多出来的清洁用品
some of my extra cleaning supplies in here!
紧急情况
Emergency!
这巨型披萨饺凉了  得马上加热
This cold jumbo calzone needs re-heating, stat!
正好
Perfect!
派大星的超大微波柜
Patrick's walk-in microwave!
马桶坏掉了
The toilet's on the fritz
我才刚喝完梅干玛奇朵咖啡
and I already had my prune macchiato!
一点都憋不住了
I can't hold it any longer!
正好
Perfect!
派大星的超大微波柜
Patrick's walk-in microwave!
我得在里面方便个六小时  所以
Alright, I'm gonna need about six hours of privacy, so--
它就这样把他们给抓了
And it grabbed 'em like this!
那样把他们咬了
And it chomped 'em like that!
没事
Don't worry.
我有个办法  可以阻止时旅柜
I've got a plan to stop the Time Closet!
我们就只要
All we have to do is--
它居然把鱿鱼妹给吃了
I can't believe it ate Squidina!
我才刚要想起来自己有妹妹的
I was just starting to remember I had a sister!
她没了  就只能靠我们自己了
With her gone, it's up to us.
得确保时旅柜不会再抓走别人才行
We have to make sure the Time Closet
doesn't get anyone else!
门你们自己用  你们你们
You keep that door to yourself, you-you-you--
马上行动
Starting now!
我们抓的是柜子
We're hunting a closet.
柜子有门
Closets have doors.
其实柜子差不多就是门
In fact, closets are mostly door!
柜子=门
你算得对  兄弟
Your math checks out, partner!
要抓住门  就得跟门一样思考
To catch a door, we have to think like doors!
可是怎么思考呢
But how?
两位朋友
Hey, fellas!
我可以帮你们解决难题
I can help you out of this jam!
我可是扇门
I'm a door!
达奇
Dutch!
你原来是门吗
You're a door?!
一直都是  派大星
Always have been, Patrick!
我可以把必备的知识通通教给你们
And I can teach you everything you need to know.
只要打开头脑中的感知之门就可以了
You just have to open
the doors of perception in your minds!
感觉有点嬉皮士的味道
Sounds kind of hippie-dippie.
没试过就别乱说话
Don't knock it till you've tried it!
敲
跨越知识的门槛
Step over the threshold of knowledge!
它只取决于一样东西
It all hinges on one thing:
铰 链
解锁出潜力
Unlocking the potential of--
派大星
Patrick!
我想到了
I get it!
门都喜欢双关笑话
All doors love puns!
我们可以讲个特别烂的笑话
We can use one of those lame jokes
智斗时旅柜
to outwit the Time Closet!
还真是
Of course!
我没听懂
I don't get it.
派大星
Say, Patrick.
门在什么时候不是门呢
When is a door not a door?
虚掩的时候
When it's a jar!
变罐子
感谢各位捧场
Thank you, folks.
我们整晚都在
We're here all night!
好了
There!
焕然一新
Good as new!
现在干嘛
What now?
你家人取代了我过去的位置
Your family took my place in the past!
现在要来穿越时空拯救他们
Now we go back in time and rescue 'em.
第一站  去石头滩救鱿鱼妹
First stop: Squidina in Rock Bottom!
好好  会去救的
Sure, sure, we could do that.
不然就先来看电视吧
Or we could watch some TV!
刚刚逃跑了老半天的  确实累死我了
Well, I am pretty tired
from all that fleeing we did earlier.
管他呢
What the heck!
先看鱿鱼妹怎么了  再去救她
We'll watch what happened to Squidina
and then rescue her!
电视派对
TV party!
我能来点爆米花吗
Can I have some popcorn?
我还要追我的剧呢
I'm watching my stories!
派大星
Patrick
我们应该是搭错
I think we're on the wrong
车了
bus
可是司机  我们得回裤头村去
But, sir, we need to get back to Bikini Bottom
对了
Oh, well
这是什么地方
Where am I?
又是什么时空
When am I?
鱿鱼妹
Squidina?
你来干什么
What are you doing here?
那个  几年后的事
Well, a few years from now--
没事
Never mind
还是先离开这吧
Let's just get outta here
这是什么地方
Where are here?
看
Look
石头滩
Rock Bottom
我不想待在这  海绵宝宝
I don't wanna be here, SpongeBob
我想回家
I wanna go home
你们两个先在这等着
Okay, you two wait here
那边有个公交总站
There's a bus station over there
我要去拿公交时刻表
so I'm gonna go get a schedule
这地方好可怕
This place is so creepy
又好有电影感
And so cinematic
鱿鱼妹
Hey, Squidina
车来了
The bus is here
鱿鱼妹
Squidina
海神王啊
Oh, Neptune
好吧
Oh, well
我就搭去裤头村的下一趟车好了
I'll grab the next bus to Bikini Bottom
然后再回到时旅柜里
and get back to the Time Closet
顺便拍点补充镜头素材
And grab some B-roll
[ B-roll：辅助主镜头的补充素材，如环境 ]
公较总占
问讯处
下一个
Next
怪模怪样
Looking bizarre
则所
不可名状
Uncanny
不良少年
Teenage ne'er-do-wells
公交
The bus
公较
公交
The bus
这下可好  又错过了一趟车
Oh great, I missed another one
我不想惹麻烦
I don't want any trouble
我只是
I'm just, uh
在等公交
waiting for the bus
一听就
Sounds
无聊
boring
对啊
Yeah
老古板才坐公交
Buses are for squares
过来搭咱便车吧
Come take a ride with us
我石头滩语有点生疏了
My Rock Bottomese is a little rusty
不用
No
谢了
thank you
拜托
Come on
下一趟公交
The next bus isn't for
好几小时不来
hours
我们要
We're gonna
搞点恶作剧
pull some pranks
超级
It'll be
好玩
fun
感觉这素材不错
It could be great footage
反正未来迟早都会来
The future will always be there
等会儿再回去也行
so I can get back to it later
好  我加入
Okay, I'm in
对了
Right
好耶
Alright
我名字叫
My name is
这位是
This is
那是迈克
And that's Mike
我是鱿鱼妹
I'm Squidina
电话
蟹堡王
Krusty Krab
有话快说
Make it quick
嗨
Hi
我想要点
I'd like to order
三百份蟹黄堡
300 Krabby Patties
不加蟹
Hold the Krabby
也不加堡
and the patty
早跟你们几个小屁孩说过别再打来了
I told you kids to stop calling here
我可以续杯吗
Could I get a refill?
这招真是
This one's
经典
a classic
我都
I can't
等不及了
wait
你们是我见过最酷的
You're the coolest kids I've ever
酷小子了
met
没什么啦
Aw, shucks
我想在这多待几天
I wanna hang here for days
过一阵子再回裤头村
Bikini Bottom can wait
还有
And so can
未来
the future
等一下
Wait
你们整到我了
You guys got me
你们啊
You guys
酷
Cool
真是的  拍到的素材都丢了
Aw, man, I lost my footage.
抱歉  鱿鱼妹
Sorry, Squidina.
不过呢  我们修好了时旅柜
But hey, we fixed the Time Closet!
干得漂亮
Good work.
而且你看  我宝贵的回忆也修好了
And look, we fixed my precious memory.
好  来找找你其他家人吧
Okay, let's find the rest of your family.
我找到老爸了
I found Dad!
老爸  你怎么会变得这么小
Hey, Dad, why are you so small?
没事  把他救回来就会变大了
Don't worry, he'll be bigger when we bring him back.
是酷乐湖
Here's Goo Lagoon!
欢迎来到酷乐湖
去救他吧
Let's go get him!
不对不对
No, no, no!
先看看才更好玩
It's more fun to watch first!
兄弟  有在附近看到个巨型披萨饺没
Hey, pal, have you seen a jumbo calzone around here?
那我继续去找了
Well, back to the hunt
能借几个这个吗
Could I borrow a couple of these?
什么
What?
是我儿子的小伙伴
Say, that was my son's little friend
不知道他有没有看到我的披萨饺
I wonder if he's seen my calzone
现在  再加上两个
And now, with the addition of two
数一下  两个棉花糖
count 'em, two marshmallows
你好啊  小子
Heya, sonny
有没有看到个超大披萨饺
Have you seen a big calzone?
嗨  星爸
Hi, Mr. Star
我现在在给大家好好表现一下自己
I'm kind of in the middle of impressing everyone
举重是吧
Pumping iron, huh?
我倒是可以给你指点几下
Yeah, I could give you a few pointers
我觉得吧
Well, I suppose
尽量张开脚踝
Keep your ankles as wide as possible
双膝并拢
Knees locked together
我比较喜欢双手交叉的握法
Cross grip is my preferred method
脊背弯曲
Back nice and rounded
头抬高
Head high
伸出舌头
Tongue out
鼻孔张开
Nostrils flared
然后开唱
And sing
没事
That's alright
让我给你做下正确示范
Let me show you how it's done
仔细看好了
Now watch closely
这招叫做
This is what they call
老爸神力
"dad strength"
星爸  真是太好笑了
Mr. Star, that was hilarious
我都不知道你原来这么搞笑
I had no idea you were so funny
拉里喜欢破裤子
Larry likes ripped pants
那样的话  我再给一条慈父忠告
In that case, here's another fatherly tip
一定要多带一条裤子
Always carry an extra pair of pants
要是别人这么搞
If it was anybody else
没多久这笑话就腻了
that joke would grow stale and tiresome before long
但我可以整天看你破裤子  这位老爹
But I could watch you
rip your pants all day long, dad-dude
为星爸欢呼吧
Let's hear it for Mr. Star
喜剧王
塞西尔
Cecil
哈哈笑蛤蜊
滑稽鱼
塞西尔
Cecil
破裤子塞西尔
Ripped Cecil
时尚
Fashion
破裤子塞西尔
Ripped Cecil
时尚
Fashion
破裤子塞西尔
Ripped Cecil
时尚
Fashion
破裤子塞西尔
Ripped Cecil
时尚
Fashion
塞西尔先生  模特都准备好了
Mr. Cecil, the models are ready
那就开破吧
Well, let 'em rip
塞西尔
Cecil
破了几千条裤子后
破裤子公司
想不到破裤子能破出这么个时尚大业
Who knew ripping my pants
would lead to a fashion empire?
塞西尔先生  外面有一大群人想见你
Mr. Cecil, there's a large group of people outside for you
一定都是我的死忠粉
Those must be my adoring fans
谢谢  琳达
Thank you, Linda
大家圣诞快
Season's greetings, everyo--
干嘛打我
What was that for?
你骗我们大冬天把衣服全撕破了
F-For convincing us to rip all our clothes
我们冷死了
in the m-middle of winter
对
Yeah
我们都冷冷冷死了
Now we're all f-f-f-freezing
现在能把他救回来了吧
Now can we pull him out of there?!
好戏正要上场呢
It's getting to the good part!
大家别激动
Now, now, everyone
我应该有你们想要的东西
I think I get what you all want
你们想要
You want
终极大撕破
the ultimate rip
什么
What?
怎么样
Well?
好不好看啊
What did you think?
抓住他
Get him
两半一起抓
Both of him
未完待续